harrisonndegwa65@gmail.com 0799204524 Nairobi, Kenya

Harrison Ndegwa

Title

Software Engineer

Summary

I am an experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Am well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. A confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

Experience

Front End Developer

Instadriver • Nairobi, Kenya 02/2021 - 09/2021

- Oversaw and managed a team of 4 software engineers to develop a vital module which was a success.
- Turned figma wireframes into well designed reusable react components
- Leveraged redux and react hooks functionalities to integrate react components with REST endpoints

Front End Developer

Way4Biz • Nairobi, Kenya 01/2020 - 01/2021

- In charge of developing user interface using reactjs for an e-commerce app.
- Leveraged react features and libraries like redux for state management, bootstrap as CSS framework to create good and friendly interface for users.
- Deployed MVP to Heroku for testing and presentation to the management

Web Developer and Designer

Pixenweb • Nairobi, Kenya 02/2018 - 12/2019

- Developed and maintained client sites using python django, Javascript J Query HTML5 and CSS3
- Created raw SQL queries to optimize db querying in PostgreSQL instance.
- Designed wordpress website ensuring responsiveness and security.
- Customized existing plugins and created new wordpress plugins with PHP to meet specific client needs.

Skills

- Javascript
- HTML
- PostgreSQL
- ReactJS
- Python
- Git
- Docker
- Jquery
- Bootstrap

- CSS
- SQL
- Node.js
- Typescript
- Ubuntu
- GitHub
- CI/CD
- Nextjs

Education

Economics

University of Nairobi • Nairobi, Kenya

10/2021

Languages

• English

Github

https://github.com/HarryNdegwa

Personal Website

https://www.harryndegwa.codes/